<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="//purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="//purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="//www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="//search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Youssef MEDAGHRI-ALAOUI - Thoughts, stories and ideas on Software CraftmanShip, Devops & Agility.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts, stories and ideas.]]></description><link>https://ymedaghri.github.io/</link><image><url>https://ymedaghri.github.io/favicon.png</url><title>Youssef MEDAGHRI-ALAOUI - Thoughts, stories and ideas on Software CraftmanShip, Devops &amp; Agility.</title><link>https://ymedaghri.github.io/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.25</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:07:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ymedaghri.github.io/author/youssef/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Behavior Driven Development (BDD) in a few words]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="kg-card-markdown"><p>In this article (which is my first one by the way 😜) I'm going to present you the Behavior Driven Development (BDD).<br>
<br>The main idea is very simple indeed, BDD is a <strong>Collaboration Technic</strong> where all the actors of the team meet together in a meeting called <strong>“The 3 Amigos”</strong> to</p></div>]]></description><link>https://ymedaghri.github.io/behavior-driven-development-bdd-in-a-few-words/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b58b92441514aa750b8ae0d</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Youssef MEDAGHRI-ALAOUI]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 17:53:58 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://ymedaghri.github.io/content/images/2018/08/rawpixel-250087-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="kg-card-markdown"><img src="https://ymedaghri.github.io/content/images/2018/08/rawpixel-250087-unsplash.jpg" alt="Behavior Driven Development (BDD) in a few words"><p>In this article (which is my first one by the way 😜) I'm going to present you the Behavior Driven Development (BDD).<br>
<br>The main idea is very simple indeed, BDD is a <strong>Collaboration Technic</strong> where all the actors of the team meet together in a meeting called <strong>“The 3 Amigos”</strong> to design <strong>stories</strong> related to a feature in the form of <strong>acceptance scenarios</strong>.</p>
<img src="https://ymedaghri.github.io/content/images/2017/08/3-amigos-mario-luigi-yoschi.png" alt="Behavior Driven Development (BDD) in a few words">
<h1 id="somecontext">Some context</h1>
<p>Imaging you are working for a company that is developing some kind of software.<br>
You are a highly skilled developer and you also play the scrum master role within a team that is composed of :</p>
<ul>
<li>1 or 2 Quality Analysts (QA or &quot;Testers&quot;)</li>
<li>3 or 4 Developers (including you)</li>
<li>1 Product Owner (PO)</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point there is something important that you should take in account :</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The three types of actors we just described (DEVs/QAs/POs) have each different objectives that are often conflicting.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="conflictingobjectives">Conflicting Objectives</h1>
<p>The PO is <strong>Business Value Focused</strong>.<br>
He needs to bring <strong>value into the product</strong>, this is the most important goal he needs to achieve, and it is not a simple one.<br>
For that he needs to gather client feedbacks and requirements (during long meetings), prioritize them, and include the relevant ones into the Software's Roadmap.<br>
Then he needs to write <strong>epics</strong> and <strong>stories</strong> to describe these requirements to both the <strong>Devs</strong> and the <strong>QAs</strong></p>
<p>Finally he needs to <strong>double check</strong> <i class="em em-man-facepalming"></i> <strong>all the stories</strong> even if these were already tested and checked by the <strong>Devs</strong> then by the <strong>QAs</strong>, because the requirements he described may not have been <strong>correctly understood</strong>.</p>
<p>On the other hand the QA is <strong>Quality Focused</strong>.<br>
He needs to ensure the product quality is always at its best.<br>
Doing so he may be too picky on some aspects that are considered low-priority by the DEV or by the PO.</p>
<p>Finally the DEV is <strong>Solution Focused</strong>.<br>
He need to implement the requirement while keeping the software well organised using technical refactorings and TDD approach.<br>
He has the more precise knowledge of how features are implemented into the software and will often found corner cases that will be missing in the stories.</p>
<h3 id="manyconflictscanoccurduetoeachactorfocus">Many conflicts can occur due to each actor focus :</h3>
<ul>
<li>QA is testing non relevant things and omitting very important use cases that have a lot of product value) --&gt; PO is MAD ! <i class="em em-angry"></i></li>
<li>QA or DEV find many missing information into the <strong>stories</strong> so they overwhelm the PO with questions</li>
<li>DEV and QA do not have the same understanding of the story, and try to knock each other out using their keyboards <i class="em em-boom"></i></li>
<li>And so on ......</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="amigos">Amigos...</h1>
<p>The name <strong>3 Amigos</strong> refers to the fact that the 3 parts that constitutes the Team (Developers, Testers, PO &amp; BusinessAnalysts) need to work together collaboratively during specific meetings dedicated to this collaboration.<br>
During these <strong>“The 3 Amigos”</strong> meeting, conversations take place between the business analyst (or PO), the developer, and the tester.<br>
Doing so, they elaborate the <strong>requirements</strong> and the <strong>acceptance criterias</strong> together.</p>
<p>At the end of the <strong>3 Amigos</strong> meeting the team has a set of <strong>acceptance criteria</strong>, but <strong>the most important aspect of this approach</strong> is that at this point they have <strong>the same understanding</strong> of all the requirements they have been discussing about.</p>
<h1 id="sharedunderstandingacceptancecriterias">Shared Understanding / Acceptance Criterias</h1>
<p>The output of the <strong>3 Amigos</strong> meeting is a set of <strong>acceptance scenarios</strong> corresponding to the requirements that contributes directly to precise business outcomes.</p>
<p>These acceptance scenarios will guide implementing the described requirements such as in the TDD approach (Test Driven Development)</p>
<p>The acceptance scenarios describes behaviors in a single notation directly accessible to any role in the Team (Given/When/Then Canvas).<br>
These are very well suited to work in relation with <strong>Cucumber</strong> automation testing tool.</p>
<h2 id="belowisanexampleofaverysimpleacceptancescenario">Below is an example of a very simple acceptance scenario :</h2>
<pre><code>Story: Returns go to stock
As a store owner
In order to keep track of stock
I want to add items back to stock when they're returned.

Scenario 1: Refunded items should be returned to stock
Given that a customer previously bought a black sweater from me
And I have three black sweaters in stock.
When he returns the black sweater for a refund
Then I should have four black sweaters in stock.

Scenario 2: Replaced items should be returned to stock
Given that a customer previously bought a blue garment from me
And I have two blue garments in stock
And three black garments in stock.
When he returns the blue garment for a replacement in black
Then I should have three blue garments in stock
And two black garments in stock.
</code></pre>
<h1 id="tryityourself">Try it yourself</h1>
<p>At this point you should have a pretty good understanding of the BDD conceptual approach.</p>
<h2 id="thegoldenruleofbdd">The Golden rule of BDD</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Having conversations<br>
Is more important than capturing conversations<br>
Is more important than automating conversations</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you want to put that in place you can view some very good presentations on BDD at the end of this article.<br>
You can also check the <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1YfKNOYakp-oUfef3w-0CuGwaF4GZXZB4XuqD8V0BElM/pub?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000&amp;slide=id.g35f391192_00">slides</a> of a presentation I made on BDD as a scrum master at my company.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MCaXumfckmQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kTLF2G1djZw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>